Athens, GA, 30605 USA

# Kushajveer Singh

(706) 461-9944 kushajreal@gmail.com kushajveersingh.com

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Full-stack developer experienced with doing API integrations, reading documentation to add new features to an existing codebase, code review processes, CI/CD testing. Self-motivated and passionate to learn new technologies and build projects on top of it. Experienced with deploying more than 6 projects on Vercel/Heroku, contributing to open-source projects on GitHub for over 5 years, and maintaining a technical blog with 16 published posts.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Georgia, Franklin College of Arts & Sciences Master of Science in Computer Science (GPA: 3.82/4.00)

Athens, GA, USA Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

Punjab Engineering College (Deemed to be University)

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering (CGPA: 7.0/10.0)

Chandigarh, India Aug 2016 – Jun 2020

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- C, C++, Python, PyTorch, Git, GitHub, Circle CI, Docker, Shell Scripting, Web Scraping, Agile (Scrum), Linux
- HTML, CSS (BEM), Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Next.js, Redux, Material UI, Stripe, Twilio, Bcrypt, OAuth, Sanity, Jest, Node.is, Express, Diango, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Full Stack Developer** 

Athens, GA, USA

Jul 2022 - current

- College of Agriculture and Environmental Sciences, UGA Implemented Node.js/Express parser to do real time Microsoft Access to PostgreSQL query conversion
  - Brought up development and production servers, including IP whitelisting and backup configuration with periodic syncing, and migrated 18 years of data from Access to PostgreSQL database
  - Automated data entry pipeline using Python/TypeScript, resulting in a reduction of time from 2 minutes per handwritten form to 25 seconds on average, by implementing autocomplete functionality for various fields
  - Rewrote the entire codebase for a proprietary language, which included converting information from a 200-page manual to a TypeScript/Next. is application and updating the gueries from Access to PostgreSQL

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

Computer Science Department, UGA

Athens, GA, USA

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Led weekly meetings and facilitated group discussions for the course Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science
- Held one-on-one office hours for 2 transfer students, covering the entire course in detail while covering practical applications of the content and mentored students on the career paths in computer science

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Google CS Research Mentorship Program**

Student

Athens, GA, USA (Remote) Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

Selected for a 12-week Google Research program among 50 candidates from across USA and Canada

## Winner TechGig CodeGladiators

Hackathon

Punjab, India May 2019 - Jul 2019

- Won the first solo place in Artificial Intelligence hackathon where 15 teams were selected from across India from a pool of about 0.6 million candidates
- Built a fully deployable and unsupervised parking space detection system using PyTorch and OpenCV
- Ability to adjust predictions based on where cars are parked over time

## Third place North-Zone IndiaSkills Nationals

Chandigarh, India Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

IT Software Solutions for Business

- Built desktop application using C# and android application using Java to win third place at IndiaSkills nationals
- Both applications fetched data from a MySQL and phpMyAdmin database setup

#### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

## Video Sharing App | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive full-stack video sharing social media app using React/Next.js/TypeScript/Tailwind CSS/ Zustand/Sanity and deployed on Vercel
- Google auth to register and login user, ability to upload, publish, share, comment on and like the videos
- Advanced search functionalities, filter by categories, profile pages, and see suggested accounts

#### YouTube Video Platform | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Material-UI web app using YouTube API and deployed on Vercel
- Implemented video section, category section, responsive channel and video cards, channel pages, video pages with ability to play videos straight from the app and see related videos

## **Chat Messaging App | GITHUB, DEMO**

- Built fully-responsive full-stack chat messaging application using React/TypeScript/Bcrypt and Stream Chat API
- Support for authentication, Twilio SMS notification, direct and group chats, emojis and reactions, GIF support
- Deployed React frontend on Vercel, and deployed Express.js backend on Heroku

### **Ecommerce Website** | <u>GITHUB</u>, <u>DEMO</u>

- Built full-responsive and scalable modern ecommerce website using Next.js/TypeScript and deployed on Vercel
- Used Next.js as backend endpoint, Stripe for managing payments, shipping rates and entire checkout process
- Manage entire content of website using Sanity, change details of products or add new products on the go

## Music Player and Discovery App | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive modern music player app using React/Next.js/Tailwind CSS/TypeScript/Redux/Shazam API
- Choose genre and view top songs, see top charts and artists for the country or worldwide
- Music player with controls to go to next/previous song, repeat, shuffle, fast forward, adjust volume
- Fully functional search and pages to explore most popular songs in the country, using IP Geolocation API
- View song's lyrics and official video, related songs, and other songs by the artist

## Group Video Chat | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built group video chat app using JavaScript/Agora, and deployed the backend on Heroku and frontend on Vercel
- Conference chat with multiple people at same time, screen share, private/group messaging, admin controls, polls
- Worked with an enterprise scale codebase and added features on top of it by reading documentation

## Restaurant Website | GITHUB, DEMO

- Converted Figma design into fully-responsive Next.js/TypeScript/CSS(BEM) web app and deployed on Vercel
- Modern UI/UX website built using CSS Flexbox/Grid, animations, and gradients

## Pathfinding Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Redux web app for visualizing pathfinding algorithms, mazegeneration algorithms deployed on Vercel
- Implemented 9 different algorithms and added random weight generation methods to visualize weighted shortest cost algorithms

#### Sort Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Deployed fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Redux web app for visualizing sorting algorithms on Vercel
- Implemented over 30 sorting algorithms, view multiple algorithms in parallel, generate 4 types of random array

#### JSON/YAML Graph Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built React/Next.js/Redux/Material-UI web app to convert JSON/YAML data into graph for improved readability
- Wrote YAML to JSON parser in TypeScript

#### **Bookstore application | GITHUB**

- Built full-stack bookstore application using HTML/CSS/JavaScript for frontend and Django/SQLite for backend
- Implemented user authentication with email, change/forgot password, edit profile, advanced search options, cart management, apply promotions, entire process for placing an order